Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, January 7th, 2025.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We're gonna talk about more land The game about more land.
Speaker 1: Let's do this get it.
Speaker 1: So, uh, Emily and I went to a Rangers game and I'm not gonna talk about the Rangers stinking it up like that.
Speaker 0: That's we've talked about that already.
Speaker 0: Yes, not gonna you know, we can talk.
Speaker 0: obviously we can just stop talking about hockey until until something changes Next season.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I feel like the the.
Speaker 1: the possible avenues are either We don't have to we stop worrying about hockey early and have we can spend that time on other things or that's what I'm doing.
Speaker 1: Or we get to watch a in a board of attempts to claw out of the bottom wildcard slot.
Speaker 1: But so we went to a hockey game like during the holiday week at MSG and I want to be very clear I this is not going to be a Disparagement of people who have never been to a hockey game before or tourists like.
Speaker 0: that is not the the lead of that's what I want To do.
Speaker 1: no, you know that could be done, but I'm not doing that here.
Speaker 1: cuz at this hockey game For reasons that range from the Rangers are stinking it up to.
Speaker 1: it was a holiday week.
Speaker 1: We're a lot holiday.
Speaker 0: Holiday games always are a higher price with higher demand and to more tourists and more people who don't usually go often Try to go to holiday games because that's when they don't have work.
Speaker 0: So people don't have work and they're like, hey is you know, it's like even my family back in the day The day after Thanksgiving we would go to AHL game because it was like hey convenient time, you know We
Speaker 1: used to sit watch the the minor league team in Detroit like kind of often on like a random Thursday.
Speaker 1: But so we're there and of course, you know We have season will have season tickets and there's a usual crowd around us like there's these two guys who are basically a Statler and Waldorf from the Muppets sitting next to us, but Didn't see any familiar faces.
Speaker 1: obviously all people who have bought those tickets or been gifted them by relatives who have the seats.
Speaker 1: and it was super obvious that a lot of these people had never been to MSG before because When the on ice like video starts playing I think 40% of all the people I could see got out their phones and videoed the whole thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the same one every game Yep, and people are all like videoing themselves with selfies and like.
Speaker 1: that was cool Especially because these people didn't seem to quite come in expecting to boo the way I came in expecting to boo That's right.
Speaker 1: But over the course of the game.
Speaker 1: I overhear a conversation behind us and bit by bit Most of the people sitting behind us started having this conversation.
Speaker 1: They clearly none of them knew each other But they are all tourists visiting in New York City.
Speaker 1: one of them was from Sweden.
Speaker 1: One of them was from somewhere out west.
Speaker 1: one of them was from somewhere in South America.
Speaker 1: Like they were all tourists who are in New York City visiting the city for the holidays who got tickets to see a hockey game.
Speaker 0: So I mean the people who are from the hockey watching countries are.
Speaker 0: I do, you know Often you hear people speaking other languages at Madison Square Garden, right?
Speaker 0: I mean anywhere in New York you hear a million languages But in Madison Square Garden the languages I hear most often you'd think well in New York the second most languages.
Speaker 0: It could be like Chinese and Spanish, but like I don't hear those at Madison Square Garden for hockey games very often you hear German Swedish French Canadian, right?
Speaker 0: Those are the Finnish one time I've heard.
Speaker 1: I think I've heard more What I assume was Quebecois French in MSG than I've heard anywhere else I've ever been.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you hear languages Unsurprisingly from hockey playing nations.
Speaker 1: Yep so I got to overhear.
Speaker 1: like these tourists all start talking to each other like as they all realize they're tourists and like talking about New York City.
Speaker 1: and one guy and this guy is who I'm talking about Start like starts interacting with all.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh, yeah I live here.
Speaker 1: and starts like talking to them about their experiences.
Speaker 1: tourists in New York City like cool It This guy sucks ass This guy was a problem.
Speaker 1: So basically over the course of the game He starts like giving them advice and they start asking him questions about the city.
Speaker 1: and it is very obvious to me as a New There's absolutely no universe unless he moved here yesterday That that guy lives in New York City based on the words.
Speaker 1: He is saying to these tourists.
Speaker 1: So some anecdote like some some examples.
Speaker 1: one of them asked like so, how should I how should I be getting around?
Speaker 1: I got in yesterday and he's like, oh, yeah, don't take the subway lift will get you anywhere in the city.
Speaker 1: Like he's telling to take lifts everywhere.
Speaker 0: Maybe he's a rich guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, are people who do that who live here?
Speaker 1: then he launches into how well the subway works.
Speaker 1: But the thing about the subway is that nobody here pays about space for it.
Speaker 1: You don't have to pay for it You should just jump over the turnstile.
Speaker 1: Everyone jumps over the turnstile.
Speaker 0: Nobody pays.
Speaker 0: some people jump over the turnstile, but hardly it's not a high percentage.
Speaker 1: Also considering that New York sometimes has a cop literally hiding around the corner waiting for someone to jump over the turnstile I don't think some random guy from the Netherlands should be jumping over a turnstile.
Speaker 0: in New York City One time after a concert we went into the subway and in that particular subway entrance It was the kind with you know, the big rotating turnstiles.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they're only there was only two.
Speaker 0: It's like you couldn't.
Speaker 0: oh, I think one of them was an exit only.
Speaker 0: So it's like it was really slowed for everyone to get through Right after this concert.
Speaker 0: It was way a lot of people using a low-capacity entrance.
Speaker 0: And so someone opened the emergency exit and everyone was like, well, here we go Wait in this line and you know miss the train or whatever by this low-capacity turnstile.
Speaker 0: And then there were two cops who were just like everyone go back.
Speaker 1: But Then they're like, oh what should we go see?
Speaker 1: and he starts giving them like advice on what to see.
Speaker 1: and he literally starts with You got to go to Times Square.
Speaker 1: That's like the coolest part of the city.
Speaker 1: That the seeing the Statue of Liberty is amazing.
Speaker 1: You got to go to that island like do the tour like.
Speaker 1: he's just giving dogshit advice.
Speaker 1: But finally and this goes on the entire game.
Speaker 1: I hear him behind me just giving the worst Staten Island.
Speaker 1: He finally someone some one of them asks him where in the city do you live?
Speaker 1: And at this point my ears are fully back like I'm just waiting to hear.
Speaker 1: way more interesting than the hockey game All right, and he says oh I live in a part of the city called Yonkers.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's not New York City.
Speaker 1: and this motherfucker left the game early even though the game was actually really close at the end Assumely because he has to go all the way the guys to get his ass back to Yonkers in a lift.
Speaker 0: So I guess you could take the train to Yonkers.
Speaker 1: yeah, yeah, I mean the train to Yonkers is great.
Speaker 1: I used to work in Yonkers Like if you don't have a ton of money and you like got to work in the city and you can't work from home.
Speaker 1: like You
Speaker 0: want your taxes to be slightly more difficult,
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, if you don't live in New York State To tell all the rest of you, you know the two other listeners If you live in New York State and you file taxes There are two weird questions that like don't exist in other places.
Speaker 1: the weird question number one Do you live in New York City?
Speaker 1: Because like New York City has its own taxes.
Speaker 1: most states don't have things like that.
Speaker 1: But there's also another item do you live in Yonkers?
Speaker 1: and if you check yes on that you got to do a whole fucking thing.
Speaker 0: I don't know what you have to do, but I just I imagine there are people who live in like Buffalo or North of Albany in the in the boonies Like.
Speaker 0: they fill out their state tax forms and every year it's like do you live in Yonkers?
Speaker 0: It's like there's another four.
Speaker 0: There's another part of the form that literally has Address.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you're asking me if I live in Yonkers.
Speaker 0: You could just look at my address and see it doesn't say Yonkers.
Speaker 0: on it Code is not the Yonkers zip code.
Speaker 1: Imagine if every time you went to the doctor They were legally obligated to ask you have you lived in Antarctica for more than six months at a time?
Speaker 1: But so also today some news.
Speaker 1: not game related news, but it's noteworthy because I have some anecdotes.
Speaker 1: New York City finally has Congestion pricing.
Speaker 1: We're the first city in the country.
Speaker 0: Dude in San Diego have some.
Speaker 1: I think it failed like it didn't work out.
Speaker 1: I saw an article today on CNN that said first major city in the country to have congestion processing.
Speaker 1: So if I'm wrong blame CNN.
Speaker 1: then a headline that I didn't read the article for.
Speaker 1: but so now it.
Speaker 1: you got to pay some money If you drive your car Anywhere south of 59th Street in Manhattan, which great like this is fantastic.
Speaker 1: and Dipschitz are mad about this for dipshit reasons.
Speaker 1: But the funny thing is the dipshits are all mad and arguing.
Speaker 1: well then you should.
Speaker 1: we should all Boycott driving so they don't get that tax revenue and like the subway mission mission accomplished.
Speaker 1: That is literally the goal.
Speaker 1: Our goal is not to raise money.
Speaker 1: Our goal is to have fewer fucking cars in Midtown because it's the most congested lease.
Speaker 0: There's a New Jersey Politician.
Speaker 0: I forget which one But he's like.
Speaker 0: he's like.
Speaker 0: listen if New York is gonna do this to us Right.
Speaker 0: We should just congestion price them and I'm like don't threaten me with a good time Sickos, haha.
Speaker 0: Yes Do it right make it bigger than ours.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 1: So I have some anic data because you know Commute to New York and I live next to one of the main car entrances into Manhattan like I can.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no real data yet though because it's cold and snowy and still close to holiday time.
Speaker 0: So, you know,
Speaker 1: but I but my anic data is I have commuted into Midtown from Queens two days and so far Crescent Street both days during rush hour has been like kinda empty which is Absolutely crazy because Crescent Street is usually an absolute shit show even on like Random midweek holiday days.
Speaker 1: like it's always a shit show during the rush hour, right?
Speaker 0: But like this many people are like changing their whole routine to avoid.
Speaker 1: It's an ad.
Speaker 1: it's like like it was like today.
Speaker 1: coming home I jaywalked across Crescent Street and there were no cars on it trying to get into Manhattan.
Speaker 0: Right, so either a Right, some of these people were taking a car when they didn't have to take a card.
Speaker 0: It wasn't actually more convenient.
Speaker 0: I could have just taken the train and it's like yeah those people for $9.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right would not take the car right but like if I needed to actually go there in a car for some reason $9 to not have to sit in that traffic.
Speaker 0: Right, and it's like okay Yeah, there is traffic if I go through the congestion zone but taking the Midtown Tunnel in the Lincoln Tunnel a lot of times Especially if there's congestion pricing making people not go that way Am I gonna go that way instead of the Verrazano or the George Russian Bridge if it's better?
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, I'll probably pay $9 and go through it if that's gonna be a better way.
Speaker 0: So it's like how.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We'll see any data.
Speaker 1: number two, you know, I work in Midtown like next to Grand Central.
Speaker 1: There were almost no like.
Speaker 1: there was no traffic.
Speaker 1: It was weird like to the point that it stood out.
Speaker 1: I took a bunch of pictures of random intersections because they're like wasn't the usual traffic?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, it was snowing.
Speaker 0: So we'll see what happens in a in, you know.
Speaker 1: But I had a day to three.
Speaker 1: the subway that I took to work and from work was the most crowded I have ever Seen it when there wasn't a problem happening like crazy crowded.
Speaker 1: Queensborough Plaza Crazy crowded to and from work both days.
Speaker 1: Grand Central the subway entrance crazy crowded.
Speaker 1: So again pure anecdotal, but we'll see.
Speaker 1: I'm just glad this past.
Speaker 1: It's a it's a small thing, but Paris Taking an anti-car stance has transformed that city in ways that Americans would see unimaginable.
Speaker 1: So this is a tiny step down a good road for the best city in the world.
Speaker 0: we got it we got to keep it because there's still a lot of people fighting to undo it.
Speaker 1: and oh the federal government like The the dictator to want to be has already talked about undoing it at the federal level.
Speaker 0: It'll be it'll be difficult cuz you know, not actually a dictator on paper.
Speaker 1: So yeah, good luck Even though everyone just keeps rolling over and capitulating Even though they don't have to.
Speaker 1: people should be making him fire them instead of just resigning.
Speaker 1: but that's the top.
Speaker 0: People are cowards just like the even you know, the governor who put in the congestion pricing.
Speaker 0: It was too cowardly to keep the $15 and lowered it to $9.
Speaker 0: Yeah bunch of cowards everybody.
Speaker 1: so in some news there's We've gotten some data about valve the company based because of some lawsuits and things that happened recently And I only want to talk about this data point.
Speaker 1: not any of the other things that are going on Just a data point.
Speaker 1: and the data point was comparing valve as a company to Facebook Apple Netflix alphabet.
Speaker 1: so Google Microsoft Intel and Amazon and Not Nvidia.
Speaker 1: Nvidia's not on this list.
Speaker 1: And there are two columns in this piece of data.
Speaker 1: column number one is Net income per hour per employee and Column two is net income per employee.
Speaker 1: So for example Facebook makes $89 an hour per employee total in net income so $780,000 per employee, I think it's per year like so if you work for them and they pay you $50 an hour That's $32 an hour.
Speaker 0: They're stealing from you.
Speaker 0: mark out of Marxism Amazon makes.
Speaker 0: if you see if you seize the means of production you would get the $82, right?
Speaker 1: So Amazon meanwhile, it makes one dollar and eighty one cents in net income per hour per employee.
Speaker 0: But they got a lot of employees and a lot of hours.
Speaker 0: that adds up to a lot of one dollars.
Speaker 1: Yep, so that that is interesting data in and of itself.
Speaker 1: But the reason we have this data point is because of lawsuits and As a result all we know because there's a redacted line at the top Valve makes more money per employee than any of those companies.
Speaker 0: It's not a surprise.
Speaker 0: valve Doesn't all those other companies right?
Speaker 0: need an employee to do some work?
Speaker 0: Yeah to get some money right if you buy something on Amazon, they need to have warehouse people doing stuff Team fortress 2 to encounter strike to exist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like valve.
Speaker 0: They don't actually need to work very hard on steam itself, right?
Speaker 0: They are developing counter-strike and some games and stuff.
Speaker 0: But it's like they don't need that.
Speaker 0: all their money comes from taking a 30% cut of all these games other people make.
Speaker 0: And when other people make games and sell them on Steam valve doesn't need to have employees working for that thing to happen.
Speaker 0: It's just an automated money-making machine and they do not as far as I'm aware Maintain it as much as they probably could or should.
Speaker 0: if you're a developer and you want to sell your game on Steam and you Need like technical support from valve people How good are they really at that?
Speaker 0: I've heard not the best.
Speaker 1: Yep Do you know how many employees valve actually has?
Speaker 0: Not a lot.
Speaker 1: Yep 79 of them work on Steam.
Speaker 1: Yep, 181 work on valves and this article quote games.
Speaker 1: unquote department doing quote whatever unquote.
Speaker 1: Well, 41 work in hardware development and 35 handle the rest of the company like admin finance HR everything else Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So valve is a very efficient company for all the reasons Scott described.
Speaker 0: and Yeah Why are the steam forums not moderated?
Speaker 0: All right, which one of the tens of people who are gonna do?
Speaker 0: yeah It's like you need an army of people to moderate those.
Speaker 0: and if they other companies Do have those armies of people doing things that they should be doing.
Speaker 0: valve It just does less things that involve humans or doesn't do things They should be doing.
Speaker 1: valve is smaller than all but one of the companies I've ever worked for in my life.
Speaker 1: Oh Dibellos Dibellos was smaller, but that doesn't count.
Speaker 1: That was the real job.
Speaker 1: Anyway got any news.
Speaker 0: We do have played at.
Speaker 0: CES is happening, which means there's a whole lot of news in the tech world.
Speaker 0: Right, but in the gaming world there is less news, but Didn't I send it to you?
Speaker 0: I'm looking.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh, there it is.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, it's not I didn't send you the news.
Speaker 0: That's why I'm.
Speaker 1: that's why I didn't know.
Speaker 1: instead.
Speaker 1: I have the I'm music thing, which is for another.
Speaker 0: No, that's that's something else entirely.
Speaker 0: That's not even on the show.
Speaker 0: Anyway, no the news is is that there are going to be two new games Gundam games that are coming tabletop Gundam games.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be a card game and there's gonna be a miniatures game.
Speaker 0: right the card game.
Speaker 0: We knew about it like unplugged.
Speaker 0: It's been announced for a little while.
Speaker 0: The miniatures game is a newer news at least to me and so the card game by all accounts.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, you get cards with pictures of Gundams on them and the cards might look real nice But it's gonna be some garbage game.
Speaker 1: CCG just like all the Japanese articles quote the highly anticipated collectible card game titled Gundam card game Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I could not imagine a more crass cash grab.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this game is gonna be probably Bad.
Speaker 0: based on my estimation there is no indication that it is going to be good.
Speaker 0: I would avoid it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the miniatures game.
Speaker 0: now here we have something going on with the miniatures game, right Yes, there might.
Speaker 0: I don't know if there's gonna be blind boxes or any collectible nonsense or not.
Speaker 0: I think they're you know, they didn't say.
Speaker 0: at least I didn't see any info about it.
Speaker 0: I suspect it won't be.
Speaker 0: I suspect it'll be more Warhammer esque where it may be overpriced.
Speaker 0: But you buy what you're gonna buy.
Speaker 0: But they're Basically, the miniatures are Gundam models.
Speaker 0: you have to cut them out and assemble them, but they're only like a couple inches tall and then you have to paint them and It's like hey Even if that game is complete shit because it's gonna be a turn-based tactical miniatures combat game right when you roll dice
Speaker 1: Happens on a seven by nine hex grid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, you know, what kind of game it's gonna be.
Speaker 0: It might have some merit.
Speaker 1: I see tens appear to be the dice they use.
Speaker 0: Yeah But it doesn't really matter he in this case if this game sucks because you could just buy two inch Gundam models and use them For whatever decoration and that's hella fun, you know, it's like what would be more fun than like one master grade?
Speaker 0: It's like what if you could buy like 32 inches?
Speaker 0: It's like hmm How many two inches can you get for the same price as like a 1/100 scale model or like an RG or whatever?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: this might be a much better value proposition.
Speaker 0: and also, you know the big models They're kind of a project right if you want to do a really good job and do painting and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Right, it takes a while and you know that has to be like close to your main hobby to actually finish.
Speaker 0: You know a bunch of them.
Speaker 0: if you're not just bored doing a lazy job Two inches you can get one of those done and a reasonable I'm not.
Speaker 0: it's not like painting.
Speaker 1: that is only about twice two or three times as much total effort as painting like a D&D miniature.
Speaker 0: That's like that's like a one afternoon activity.
Speaker 0: Yeah right there Maybe not even like.
Speaker 0: you can get your you can have all your friends come over and everyone can like paint a two-incher and then You'd still have time to do other things Once.
Speaker 1: I haven't done a mini painting in a long time.
Speaker 0: I do a little paint and take.
Speaker 0: I did one at West.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know do it once in a while.
Speaker 1: I was gonna do one at West but Painting minis is actually.
Speaker 0: I don't know if miniature war games are gaining in popularity, but painting is Going.
Speaker 1: there were three different paint and take areas of packs unplugged.
Speaker 1: that I saw right.
Speaker 0: But I mean like there are new paint brands coming out.
Speaker 0: That is how hot miniatures painting is right now, so There you go.
Speaker 1: But anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 1: so I remember a long long time ago One of our favorite things on the internet high space the fake Myspace.
Speaker 1: that was just like in the fictional world of the Legend of Zelda and it was just like a full acute experience of clicking around and seeing what like Epona or Milan think and post about like a link and Zelda like.
Speaker 1: It was just.
Speaker 1: it was a cute thing that I don't think exists on the internet anymore.
Speaker 1: I've stumbled onto and Emily actually is what appointed me at this the closest thing to that.
Speaker 1: I've seen in a long time.
Speaker 1: It's a tumbler, but it is called temperate lake dashboard simulator And it is a fake tumbler of all the fish that live in a temperate lake And frogs and other things having the kinds of conversations animals like that would have if they could talk about the lake Mmm.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it was funnier than it has any right to be and I Thoroughly enjoy this like for example.
Speaker 1: I just migrated here from Instagram.
Speaker 1: Please be nice.
Speaker 1: the picture of post I post of myself versus the picture of the biologist jaw tagging me in.
Speaker 0: So what he got So back in the day on Twitter.
Speaker 0: right one of the positive things about Twitter was that people would make accounts That would be collections of various things.
Speaker 0: right one of the good ones like the PC 98 pot.
Speaker 0: That would be all screenshots from.
Speaker 0: you know, PC 98 games pixel or a famous one about pixel That was a tumbler, you know, there was the Simpson quote one, right?
Speaker 0: There are a lot like that.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I think the new social media world where I don't exist because I've given up all that shit Needs some more of those right.
Speaker 0: and so here's one on Mastodon dot world obsolete Sony and It's pretty much exactly what it sounds like.
Speaker 0: it is just a collection of old obsolete forgotten and obscure Sony products and devices And some of them are just like old PlayStation which when you see it, you're like, oh, I guess I'm old If you consider that an obsolete device.
Speaker 0: but some of them are really amazing.
Speaker 0: things like Sony Ericsson phones that I've never seen before or The Sony hit bit computers, those are really.
Speaker 1: I can't get past.
Speaker 1: the remote control for the 1986 Sony beta Pro SLHF 900 and mark - Holy shit, that is the most amazing remote control I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they got a lot of good shit on here.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment, we're gonna be at magfest.
Speaker 1: It's coming up and a little birdie told me that magfest is about to sell out.
Speaker 0: So even though the price has gone up it would sell out completely.
Speaker 0: that's a you know That's.
Speaker 1: uh, I'm telling you there is a deep deep hunger among the people who like conventions do go to conventions.
Speaker 0: This could be a problem because right now magfest, you know, you have the hotel problem, but you haven't had the badge fight problem.
Speaker 0: What if there is a badge fight for future mag fests badge fight and hotel?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I assume did you get your email about your panelist badge?
Speaker 1: Yes, okay.
Speaker 1: It's just making sure.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the schedule is, but I did get.
Speaker 0: I have.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: I will post our schedule of at least three panels.
Speaker 0: listener emailed asking for the schedule and I said I don't even know it yet and rim will post it on the website once.
Speaker 1: I will in fact post it In the net either today or tomorrow.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to confirm if there's more than three But there'll be at least three Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: All right, but I'm super hungry.
Speaker 1: So let's get right into it and talk about a new board game a board game to review reviewing board games on gig nights.
Speaker 1: We played a new board game that we can review.
Speaker 0: What is the last time we went to packs?
Speaker 0: that we went to packs unplugged and rim didn't miss the packs for what?
Speaker 0: yeah, and So there were games there that we played that we had never played previously that we played together and so we couldn't discuss them.
Speaker 1: Yep, so more land hit the table twice at this packs unplugged Game for 2023.
Speaker 0: so it's not the newest but it's new to us and it's new to probably most people listening.
Speaker 1: and I will say right now more land.
Speaker 1: I had mechanics I have not seen before and Wasn't bad.
Speaker 1: Like I enjoyed my time with it.
Speaker 1: A friend of ours actually bought it at the convention.
Speaker 1: I thought about buying it.
Speaker 1: the only reason I waited is that I didn't have any ruin my luggage to take it home and I always been that big.
Speaker 0: it's it's kind of a normal size one.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but my luggage was packed to the brim because I packed very very minimally with a tiny tiny suitcase.
Speaker 1: Yeah but more land is interesting in that It's about moors like the moors in Scotland but it's also kind of a pun because you're literally playing tiles that are land and The theme is that you are basically Curating and like making a more.
Speaker 1: like you're digging the little trenches for the water and you're planting The the plants to make a thriving ecosystem and you're all competing In your own separate boards for who makes the best more Ecosystem by the end of the game.
Speaker 0: it is supposed to be like an educational thing to some extent and in fact if when you buy this game some of your money goes to like the Global Nature Fund to help protect, you know The environment or whatever that Global Nature Fund does I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know much about them, but There's a big thing on the box.
Speaker 0: It's like save the moors.
Speaker 0: buy this game.
Speaker 0: You'll help save the moors just by buying it and then you can pretend in roleplay saving the moors by playing it.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it's a pretty good game.
Speaker 1: It's got some stuff going on.
Speaker 1: So basically everyone gets their own board to put tiles on But you're all drawing tiles to play from a pool and you rotate like who goes first picking a tile and The tiles have stuff on them, but the resource in the game is basically on those tiles.
Speaker 1: You'll get plants of different types plus other things on the tiles Like this tile has a frog on it or this tile has what a water strider on it And those are all part of our snake and those are all part of the scoring at the end of the game And When you pick a tile up You can either place it right away or just hold on to it not place it.
Speaker 1: But once you pick up your third tile.
Speaker 1: if they're if you pick one up and there's three in front of you Well now you've got to play all three right the fuck.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: And if it turns out that you can't play all three in a way that you wanted to You are stuck playing them and if it ruins you it ruins you.
Speaker 1: So you kind of like how much of a combo can you build up before you gotta throw it out?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean most games, you know that have you know?
Speaker 0: buying things with resources.
Speaker 0: You collect the resources in a pile and then you just spend them in this game.
Speaker 0: any resource you collect is going to be on one of the tiles on your board in Like a you know, just sort of like.
Speaker 0: they each have six spaces on them.
Speaker 0: Yep, so it'll just be like it, you know, they can hold six things and so Every tile that you can place has a cost Associated with it.
Speaker 0: like ah, if you want to play this tile It has to be on an empty space that has at least two white pieces just sitting there waiting right, and then so the cost has to be Already like ready in the location that the tiles gonna go.
Speaker 0: So even if you have two white and but they're separate from each other or they're in the wrong spots You might not be able to play, you know a tile that cost two white.
Speaker 0: You got to arrange it in advance and so that's pretty clever and interesting.
Speaker 0: the other thing is that once you play a tile obviously the resources that go towards the cost those get spent any if there's extra resources because there probably will be on that spot that Weren't used for the construction of the new tile.
Speaker 1: They flow down the river To another tile the river they will have made of all the tiles you've played so far Exactly.
Speaker 0: See they flow down the river to a new free space to where they can now await you playing your next tile.
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like this cascade of it not sort of it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah You put the resources in some spots.
Speaker 0: you Play tiles on those spots Removing some of the resources and the rest of the resources float downstream to where you can play more cards and you have to manage this in such a way that you don't get stuck where.
Speaker 0: So many ways to get stuck.
Speaker 0: resources can't flow because the river is bad The you can't play a tile because the wrong mix of resources are.
Speaker 0: on a tile.
Speaker 1: There's you.
Speaker 1: there's nowhere for resources to go.
Speaker 1: You just take negative victory points.
Speaker 1: Like you're F'd.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's just like so many ways for this to go wrong.
Speaker 0: a tile is completely full of resources But they don't match like any of the things that you can play.
Speaker 0: So they're just sort of stuck there with the victory point salad.
Speaker 1: That's kind of how the game scores.
Speaker 1: It's a little more like Agricola in that you kind of got a balance everything and you're trying to make the most balanced Possible board.
Speaker 1: if you yeah hammer one thing too hard It probably won't help you win and you're probably gonna take some negative points because you messed up something else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can always I think you can always flip a tile over to the backside where it's like a plus tile.
Speaker 0: It's like the safety tile, but it actually sucks for you to do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah But yeah it's like you.
Speaker 0: the the tiles come out the ones the river ones that you get to place and you're just purchasing and you sort of draft them around the table and It's like you might be looking and it's like yeah when you're going first you get your pick of them and you can pick one.
Speaker 0: That's good for you that you know You can afford to play and it matches your river nicely and it's gonna work out.
Speaker 0: Well, but then next turn you go last and see now you're gonna have to take a tile And it's you had to be able to occasionally deal with.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna have to play something No matter what and it might not be good But that I had to be resilient enough to and have enough Flexible resources to deal with whatever gets drawn from that deck.
Speaker 1: now That is I think the most clever mechanic because the flowing of the resources is really cool Like I haven't seen that in a game before and I like it a lot.
Speaker 1: but the the fact that you if you take a tile You can play it immediately or wait and then you can build up like a reservoir of up to three But then your force it's like a little buffer because in a lot of games where you draft tiles if you go last Like you just get fucked and there's nothing you can do about it in this case.
Speaker 1: I go last.
Speaker 1: Well, I just don't play it I take a tile.
Speaker 1: I take the best tile I can.
Speaker 1: I put it in front of me I don't play it yet.
Speaker 1: And now my mission is to pick up a different tile in the next round that I'm gonna pick one up to try to like mitigate the harm of that bad tile or turn that by tile into a good tile.
Speaker 1: and I can do this up to three.
Speaker 1: It's like the buffer but once I've got my third tile Well, if I've just kept kicking that can down the road and I've got three bad tiles.
Speaker 1: Well now I'm screwed.
Speaker 1: Another thing our zone.
Speaker 1: you could draw tile and instead of playing it hang on to it and then eventually play all three tiles in one big turn.
Speaker 0: One thing I thought actually the most interesting mechanic is that for generating the the seed?
Speaker 0: Wooden pieces they're generated from the blank not yet covered tiles Alright, so that have the six spaces on them.
Speaker 0: So though your board starts out where like you have two different ones that can generate wild which means anything And you've got some that could generate all the different colors, but it's like, okay Eventually you cover up your one that can play generates.
Speaker 0: You know white resources whatever they are and now it's you can't really generate more white ones.
Speaker 1: It's a little different from that.
Speaker 1: Remember the.
Speaker 1: each tile generates a different number of resources.
Speaker 1: like if you pick this tile You're gonna get three of something.
Speaker 1: if you pick this other tile You're gonna get one and you might be asking but wouldn't I always want to pick the three?
Speaker 1: Well one you might want to cover that three with a tile and now you can't generate things there anymore.
Speaker 1: But two it is really easy to have too many resources.
Speaker 1: I Did not win in fact, I did very badly the first time I played because I thought you know typical rim style heuristic.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna generate as many resources as I can to be flexible for the second half of the game.
Speaker 1: And then at the end of the game, I had a pile of resources I couldn't spend.
Speaker 1: and that's all negative points.
Speaker 0: I played this game and I absolutely dominated.
Speaker 0: It wasn't even close.
Speaker 0: it was not close and basically this I think this is actually the bad thing about the game.
Speaker 0: Is that for all this cleverness and interesting this I pretty much found what I believe to be the answer right away.
Speaker 1: I don't think what you did is the most possible often way to play but oh, no I was actually.
Speaker 0: I could have gotten three more points.
Speaker 0: I was too careful.
Speaker 0: if I had been more reckless and played shittier I would have had three more points than I had At the end of the game.
Speaker 0: because there's these lily pads that you get on your tiles and basically Resources when they flow down the river that because you didn't use them You can instead of landing them and in an empty space to use for your next tile You can land them on a lily pad as like a safety, you know a valve.
Speaker 0: We're like, oh this resource that I can't rescue.
Speaker 0: I'll get it on a lily pad.
Speaker 0: that way I'm safe.
Speaker 1: some of those turn into victory points and some of those right remove it for you So you don't have to deal with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but every full lily pad gives you a point and But they're like a safety valve.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, okay I'll try to be really efficient and not have to use them.
Speaker 0: and then I assume just because the game has this Difficulty factor of where of course, you can't use everything that at the end of the game I'll have some spares and I'll fill up the lily pads.
Speaker 0: I was so careful and so precise that at the end of the game at empty lily pads I had three empty lily pads.
Speaker 0: if I had been reckless and just taken some extra resources that even if I knew I couldn't use Them and they would damage me.
Speaker 0: I actually had lily pads to spare Yeah, and would have gotten more points by being more us all out of the water.
Speaker 0: Yes, I blew you out of the water with the basic strategy, which was the snake strategy.
Speaker 0: basically, I just went.
Speaker 0: I focused on the river.
Speaker 0: make it try because there are 16 tiles on the board and you get this points for like getting the longest contiguous river.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, oh well I'll just make a 16 length river and any other points I get along.
Speaker 0: the way is gravy.
Speaker 0: and so I started in one spot and I moved all the resources to one place and Then I put a tile there and I just drew this path with the river That would take up all the spaces on the board and I put tiles out one at a time and I
Speaker 1: food
Speaker 0: all the resources Just to the head of the snake and I just said, all right I'm taking whatever tile goes on the head of the snake and I'm gonna move all the leftover resources to where the new head of The snake is.
Speaker 0: literally like I was playing snake with the apple eating.
Speaker 1: Yep, or like I was just cursor and you're just moving it around Right.
Speaker 0: It's like Tron and I'm just trying to fill up the board for some reason without crashing, right?
Speaker 0: And so I ended up getting a river of 15 spaces not 16.
Speaker 0: I was one.
Speaker 0: Oh, I was a little less perfect there.
Speaker 0: But yeah, that's that's the strategy.
Speaker 0: I think I'm pretty sure if you do that you can't do better.
Speaker 1: But I guess I think there are.
Speaker 1: there might be a way to do better But it would.
Speaker 0: I don't have had 60.
Speaker 0: I could have had a 16 length river and I could have used those lily pads.
Speaker 0: I've been a little more reckless.
Speaker 0: I would had but I still won by like 10 points out something.
Speaker 1: So but it does have a nice.
Speaker 1: everyone's making their own Like tile area.
Speaker 1: so it's kind of like here's the situation you all have the same Like.
Speaker 1: you all have the same agency except for the drafting of the tiles.
Speaker 1: who does the best job optimizing the ecosystem?
Speaker 1: but they have a little incentive in that there's this clever little set of cards you put out and For any given position in anyone's board, whoever plays the first tile there gets a water drop.
Speaker 1: that's basically effectively a victory point like it's sort of a get out of jail free card for a resource and It incentivizes trying to play in a place.
Speaker 1: No one else has played before first.
Speaker 1: But overall like it was a pleasant game.
Speaker 1: it does not take long to play.
Speaker 1: it does not take that long to teach though It.
Speaker 1: I think teaching it.
Speaker 1: people don't really get it until they've played a few rounds and then they get it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's all you.
Speaker 0: only thing that's I think really hard to get is just you know Yeah, when you need to put a tile on a spot that already has the you know, the cost involved, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if it was a magic card that cost, you know, two forest and an island or two green mana and a blue mana.
Speaker 0: It's like not only do you need two green and a blue to buy it?
Speaker 0: You need to have two green and a blue in the spot that you want to put in and that's that's how it works.
Speaker 1: Yeah but prompts at this game for having Two novel mechanics that I have not seen before in games that I'd like to see in more games and being a pretty pleasant experience That you know, our panel at PAX was take your fucking turn how to go quickly.
Speaker 1: This game does not overstay its welcome.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty young thing.
Speaker 0: The game plays fast because you know this drafting goes in a circle But it's just literally pick one of these cards and then everyone could sort of do their own thing You're not?
Speaker 0: there's not a lot of waiting going on right in this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah But Yeah, I think that the for usually like the sort of educational do-good nonprofit promotional type games Usually don't hit.
Speaker 0: very Christian video games don't do well.
Speaker 1: Well, here's what I found.
Speaker 1: Those games are either typically accurate in some meaningful way to the thing but are not fun as a result because the thing isn't fun as a game or They're thematically accurate, but the gameplay has nothing to do with the theme So they just don't feel good or they're just bad.
Speaker 1: This one actually is true to the theme Like in a mechanical and thematic way and it's fun to play.
Speaker 0: that is really fucking hard to do You know, so would I buy this game?
Speaker 0: No, well, no cuz Alex bought it sure, but I mean Would I play this game again?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I would I play this game again?
Speaker 0: a lot?
Speaker 0: No But I think if you have like a classroom or a library?
Speaker 1: Oh, this should absolutely be in the packs table top library, you know.
Speaker 0: Or you know, maybe you have like an Airbnb.
Speaker 0: the families stay at man, right?
Speaker 0: It's like this is the kind of game that kind of situation.
Speaker 0: Right, you know people can play a few times.
Speaker 0: All right, they'll be able to learn it, but they'll still get you know value out of it.
Speaker 0: It'll be a you know a deeper experience than the other games they're playing.
Speaker 0: but I think that the the hardcore type gamers looking for like the deep strategies will Only get so many plays out of the rim and Scott played this multiple times in a row.
Speaker 1: My guess is two more plays and will have proven that there are.
Speaker 1: there's one or two Optimal strategies and we wouldn't be making decisions anymore is my guess.
Speaker 0: But If you're in the game designing realm at least read the rule book because you'll see there's some things I saw that I don't see and someone who's seen as many games as I seen that's rare and also therefore know therefore notable.
Speaker 1: We're well written and you know, that's a sticking point for us like yeah My favorite graphic design the rules everything production wise.
Speaker 0: there were no issues Which is actually?
Speaker 1: Not common, yeah, like.
Speaker 1: overall I would give this game an a not in the sense of like, is it a game?
Speaker 1: I will play forever because the bar for that is impossible But because it's like a super well-designed game that does everything it intended to do.
Speaker 0: So it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like a mission accomplished situation, you know, great great job.
Speaker 0: you did.
Speaker 0: what you're gonna do Not not an all-time masterpiece, but not everything has to be all-time masterpiece.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like you made the perfect painting to like.
Speaker 0: hang in that Dennis office You know, you couldn't do better just cuz it's not gonna hang in the Louvre.
Speaker 0: doesn't mean that like you suck or something by Stefan Baughan.
Speaker 1: so props to you, but Clicking on the linked games in board game keep right now.
Speaker 1: The other game that you appear to have designed is camel up.
Speaker 0: Well camel up it might be closer to the Louvre.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Stefan Baughan, uh, you're all.
Speaker 1: you're a good game designer.
Speaker 1: I would say I would agree.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: clue calm for show notes discussion links and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows Mondays or science and technology Tuesdays gaming and games.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are animation and comics.
Speaker 1: Thursdays are arbitrary and indiscriminate.
Speaker 1: Ignites is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 4.0 International license.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce, Link Iggy, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Chris the dog, Christopher O'Rourke, Clinton, Walton, Finn, Joel Haze, Penny Reimer, Rebecca Don, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Horrell and a bunch of people whose names I will not say.
Speaker 1: Moreland was pretty fun.
Speaker 1: Tonight, I'm gonna eat some ramen.
Speaker 1: So I'm just gonna leave you with.
Speaker 0: I read a book about this sort of thing once.
Speaker 0: are you sure it was a book?
Speaker 0: Are you sure it wasn't nothing?
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah.